se_net_questions = [
{
        "question": "A user is curious about how someone might know a computer has been infected with malware. Which is a common malware behavior?",
        "options": [
            "a) The computer emits a hissing sound every time the pencil sharpener is used.",
            "b) The computer beeps once during the boot process.",
            "c) The computer gets increasingly slower to respond.."
            "d) No sound emits when an audio CD is played.",
        ],
        "answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What functional area of the Cisco Network Foundation Protection framework is responsible for device-generated packets required for network operation, such as ARP message exchanges and routing advertisements?",
        "options": [
            "a) data plane",
            "b) control plane",
            "c) management plane",
            "d) forwarding plane"
        ],
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "A security service company is conducting an audit in several risk areas within a major corporation. What statement describes the risk of using social networking?",
        "options": [
            "a) sensitive data lost through access to the cloud that has been compromised due to weak security settings",
            "b) gaining illegal access to corporate data by stealing passwords or cracking weak passwords",
            "c) data loss through access to personal or corporate instant messaging and social media sites",
            "d) the retrieval of confidential or personal information from a lost or stolen device that was not configured to use encryption software"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "A security service company is conducting an audit in several risk areas within a major corporation. What statement describes the risk of access to removable media?",
        "options": [
            "a) the potential of causing great damage because of direct access to the building and its infrastructure devices",
            "b) intercepted emails that reveal confidential corporate or personal information",
            "c) the unauthorized transfer of data containing valuable corporate information to a USB drive",
            "d) data loss through access to personal or corporate instant messaging and social media sites"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of a reconnaissance attack on a computer network?",
        "options": [
            "a) to gather information about the target network and system",
            "b) to redirect data traffic so that it can be monitored",
            "c) to prevent users from accessing network resources",
            "d) to steal data from the network servers"
        ],
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "A security service company is conducting an audit in several risk areas within a major corporation. What statement describes an internal threat?",
        "options": [
            "a) data loss through access to personal or corporate instant messaging and social media sites",
            "b) the unauthorized transfer of data containing valuable corporate information to a USB drive",
            "c) the potential of causing great damage because of direct access to the building and its infrastructure devices",
            "d) gaining illegal access to corporate data by stealing passwords or cracking weak passwords"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the data protection functions provided by MDM?",
        "options": [
            "a) remote wiping",
            "b) inoculation",
            "c) quarantine",
            "d) physical security"
        ],
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which security measure is best used to limit the success of a reconnaissance attack from within a campus area network?",
        "options": [
            "a) Implement restrictions on the use of ICMP echo-reply messages.",
            "b) Implement a firewall at the edge of the network.",
            "c) Implement access lists on the border router.",
            "d) Implement encryption for sensitive traffic."
        ],
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an evasion method used by hackers?",
        "options": [
            "a) scanning",
            "b) access attack",
            "c) phishing",
            "d) encryption"
        ],
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which attack involves threat actors positioning themselves between a source and destination with the intent of transparently monitoring, capturing, and controlling the communication?",
        "options": [
            "a) man-in-the-middle attack",
            "b) SYN flood attack",
            "c) DoS attack",
            "d) ICMP attack"
        ],
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the motivation of a white hat attacker?",
        "options": [
            "a) fine tuning network devices to improve their performance and efficiency",
            "b) taking advantage of any vulnerability for illegal personal gain",
            "c) studying operating systems of various platforms to develop a new system",
            "d) discovering weaknesses of networks and systems to improve the security level of these systems"
        ],
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "A user is curious about how someone might know a computer has been infected with malware. Which is a common malware behavior?",
        "options": [
            "a) The computer emits a hissing sound every time the pencil sharpener is used.",
            "b) The computer beeps once during the boot process.",
            "c) No sound emits when an audio CD is played.",
            "d) The computer freezes and requires reboots."
        ],
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which security feature or device would more likely be used within a CAN than a SOHO or data center?",
        "options": [
            "a) security trap",
            "b) ESA/WSA",
            "c) virtual security gateway",
            "d) wireless router",
            "e) exit sensors"
        ],
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "A company has several sales offices distributed within a city. Each sales office has a SOHO network. Which security feature is commonly found in such a network configuration?",
        "options": [
            "a) biometric verifications",
            "b) Virtual Security Gateway within Cisco Nexus switches",
            "c) Cisco ASA firewall",
            "d) port security on user facing ports"
        ],
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the data protection function provided by MDM?",
        "options": [
            "a) PIN locking",
            "b) inoculation",
            "c) quarantine",
            "d) physical security"
        ],
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which condition describes the potential threat created by Instant On in a data center?",
        "options": [
            "a) when the primary firewall in the data center crashes",
            "b) when an attacker hijacks a VM hypervisor and then launches attacks against other devices in the data center",
            "c) when the primary IPS appliance is malfunctioning",
            "d) when a VM that may have outdated security policies is brought online after a long period of inactivity."
        ],
        "answer": "d"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which interfaces or ports can security be improved by configuring executive timeouts?",
        "options": [
            "a) Fast Ethernet interfaces",
            "b) serial interfaces",
            "c) loopback interfaces",
            "d) vty ports"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which command will block login attempts on RouterA for a period of 30 seconds if there are 2 failed login attempts within 10 seconds?",
        "options": [
            "a) RouterA(config)# login block-for 10 attempts 2 within 30",
            "b) RouterA(config)# login block-for 30 attempts 2 within 10",
            "c) RouterA(config)# login block-for 2 attempts 30 within 10",
            "d) RouterA(config)# login block-for 30 attempts 10 within 2"
        ],
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "A network administrator enters the service password-encryption command into the configuration mode of a router. What does this command accomplish?",
        "options": [
            "a) This command encrypts passwords as they are transmitted across serial WAN links.",
            "b) This command prevents someone from viewing the running configuration passwords.",
            "c) This command enables a strong encryption algorithm for the enable secret password command.",
            "d) This command automatically encrypts passwords in configuration files that are currently stored in NVRAM.",
            "e) This command provides an exclusive encrypted password for external service personnel who are required to do router maintenance."
        ],
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which interfaces or ports can security be improved by configuring executive timeouts?",
        "options": [
            "a) Fast Ethernet interfaces",
            "b) serial interfaces",
            "c) console ports",
            "d) loopback interfaces"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "A security service company is conducting an audit in several risk areas within a major corporation. What statement describes an attack vector?",
        "options": [
            "a) data loss through access to personal or corporate instant messaging and social media sites",
            "b) the path by which a threat actor can gain access to a server, host, or network",
            "c) intercepted emails that reveal confidential corporate or personal information",
            "d) the unauthorized transfer of data containing valuable corporate information to a USB drive"
        ],
        "answer": "b"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of mobile device management (MDM) software?",
        "options": [
            "a) It is used to implement security policies, setting, and software configurations on mobile devices.",
            "b) It is used to create a security policy.",
            "c) It is used to identify potential mobile device vulnerabilities.",
            "d) It is used by threat actors to penetrate the system."
        ],
        "answer": "a"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which security implementation will provide management plane protection for a network device?",
        "options": [
            "a) antispoofing",
            "b) routing protocol authentication",
            "c) role-based access control",
            "d) access control lists"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
    },
    {
        "question": "A security service company is conducting an audit in several risk areas within a major corporation. What statement describes the risk of access to cloud storage devices?",
        "options": [
            "a) intercepted emails that reveal confidential corporate or personal information",
            "b) gaining illegal access to corporate data by stealing passwords or cracking weak passwords",
            "c) sensitive data lost through access to the cloud that has been compromised due to weak security settings",
            "d) the retrieval of confidential or personal information from a lost or stolen device that was not configured to use encryption software"
        ],
        "answer": "c"
    }

]
